<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>trootski</title><link>http://localhost:1313/</link><description>Recent content on trootski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Story Templates</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2019/04/story-templates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2019/04/story-templates/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been looking after some JIRA boards recently. Our team has developed some templates for outlining the requirements. We use the following ticket types:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Epic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Story&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improvement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bug&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Acer V5-122P display driver issue</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2019/03/acer-v5-122p-display-driver-issue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2019/03/acer-v5-122p-display-driver-issue/</guid><description>I had a rather disappointing experience recently with an Acer laptop that I&amp;rsquo;d like to make a note of. I think the crux of the issue is a difference between the latest driver available and the best driver for a machine.
The details are that the laptop is an Acer Aspire V5-122P. It is a cheap and cheerful laptop that I purchased for the following reasons:
Backup machine in case my daily driver broke down, Low powered machine to test performance of websites, Laptop I could take travelling without undue stress as to it&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing.</description></item><item><title>My favourite bash shortcuts</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/10/my-favourite-bash-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/10/my-favourite-bash-shortcuts/</guid><description>I recently transitioned from using vi mode in bash to the default command line shortcuts. I had ignored them for a long time but after a brief period sitting and learning a few I no longer missed vi mode. Some of the key reasons that prompted me to change are:
vi mode does not have a visual prompt, leading to unecassary escape smashing I only used the most basic motion command, eschewing a lot of the power of the vi commands When ssh&amp;rsquo;ing into other boxes the switch in interface is jarring.</description></item><item><title>What I’ve learned about cucumber js</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/03/what-ive-learned-about-cucumber-js/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/03/what-ive-learned-about-cucumber-js/</guid><description>CucumberJS is a NodeJS implementation of a test runner which is powered by the Gherkin syntax. It&amp;rsquo;s integration with our team workflow has been a boon to clarity of purpose for stories in firstly SCRUM and now KANBAN. Here I will share some of things we&amp;rsquo;re doing and the benefits we reap.
When writing a story the team gathers around a screen and we work on a shared text. Straight away this increases collaboration and removes a lot of later disagreements around &amp;lsquo;I thought we said we would do X after Y&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Delete last word</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/02/delete-last-word/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2018/02/delete-last-word/</guid><description>Coming from vim I´m used to a wide variety of keystrokes to manipulate text. The other day at work though my mind was blown when a colleague hit alt + backspace to delete the previous word in macOS. This was particularly useful because in Terminal I am used to pressing ctrl+w. This will delete the previous word as well, but it terminal it does not respect delimeters such as ´_/´_ or ´_-´_.</description></item><item><title>Back to Windows</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2016/02/back-to-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2016/02/back-to-windows/</guid><description>I recently put Windows 10 onto my little Acer. It was a practical decision. I enjoyed Ubuntu but had a real problem with the impact on battery performance. After 40 to 50 minutes the battery would generally be depleted.
So, I downloaded a Windows 8 ISO from Microsoft and began the installation. It took a loooooong time (it&amp;rsquo;s not a very performant laptop). Eventually I got Windows 8 installed, upgraded to Windows 10, sorted out activation issue with Acer and Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>Outlook Kung-Fu</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/11/outlook-kung-fu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/11/outlook-kung-fu/</guid><description>While in the process of doing some HTML emails recently I had some issues with Outlook.
Stinky, sneaky Outlook. I learned a few little techniques though that are worth sharing.
Only show this on Outlook First and foremost, only show the content between the conditionals on Outlook.
&amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;!--\[if gte mso 9\]&amp;amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;/pre&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;only on outlook&amp;#34;&amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;/div&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;!\[endif\]--&amp;amp;amp;amp;gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t show this on Outlook (v1) Anything with the style mso-hide: all will be hidden on Outlook.</description></item><item><title>Migrate Wordpress Database</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/09/migrate-wordpress-database/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/09/migrate-wordpress-database/</guid><description>I recently found the WP-CLI library and have been investigating ways I can integrate it into my workflow. I should note here that we use shared hosting extensively. Ideally the preferred solution would be to use a true migration tool. This is not always possible with shared hosting.
To use the tool the following commands would be issued:
migrate_wordpress.sh dev production This command would pull the latest version of the wordpress database from the production server.</description></item><item><title>Quick Tip: Photoshop save slices without creating images folder</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/08/quick-tip-photoshop-save-slices-without-creating-images-folder/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2015/08/quick-tip-photoshop-save-slices-without-creating-images-folder/</guid><description>One of the minor annoyances that I run into from time to time is saving slices from a PSD.
Once I have my slices defined and selected a folder Photoshop will save all my images in the folder I specified. However it will also create an images folder and place the images this folder. This means I that after saving the files they must be moved out of this folder.</description></item><item><title>ssh as part of my workflow</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/12/ssh-as-part-of-my-workflow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/12/ssh-as-part-of-my-workflow/</guid><description>Have you ever been in the situation where the discovery of a technology or technique has rendered previous workflow comically inept and wasteful. One such example would be the discovery of the &amp;ldquo;edit multiple frames&amp;rdquo; button in Adobe Flash Professional. I had spent so much time moving from frame to frame to edit a tween. Then to discover that I could choose the entire animation as one and edit. Joy and sorrow in the one same wave of realisation.</description></item><item><title>Early PC top 5</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/12/early-pc-top-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/12/early-pc-top-5/</guid><description>While doing my recent top 5 Amiga games, I got to thinking about the early PC games that I also enjoyed. I got into PC gaming in the late 90s and early noughties. Please note, these are merely the games that I particularly enjoyed:
X-Wing: Alliance Included in this is the entire X-Wing series, but I started with Alliance. Needs a joystick, but the inclusion of the requirement to manage your ship&amp;rsquo;s energy (lasers/shields/engines) adds another dimension.</description></item><item><title>Amiga Top Five</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/11/amiga-top-five/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/11/amiga-top-five/</guid><description>I was thinking recently about the amount of time I spent playing games when I was younger. I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much appetite any longer for playing games. The only game I play now is Team Fortress 2, and even that very irregularly. The only game that would probably take me back into the market is Half Life 3&amp;hellip;
So, to archive my gaming childhood, I decided to put together the accompanying list.</description></item><item><title>Vagrant and Puppet setup</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/10/vagrant-and-puppet-setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/10/vagrant-and-puppet-setup/</guid><description>This summer during my holidays in Romania I looked into Vagrant. I had some time during the due to the heat, undertaking my own siesta without the sleep.
My path to to Vagrant was slightly oblique, as I had been looking to test out Puppet. I had been using VirtualBox virtual machines as an integral part of my development and testing process for some time. The promise of making this an automated and scripted process for my development environment appealed to me.</description></item><item><title>New Rig</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/01/new-rig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2014/01/new-rig/</guid><description>As a sort of follow up to the article here I decided to continue to attempt to scratch my Linux itch.
Reasoning that maybe virtual machines aren&amp;rsquo;t a fair reflection of a system&amp;rsquo;s capabilities I went and bought a little netbook. I went for a little Acer Aspire in the January sales. This is a relatively cheap model, but it was the Christmas break so I had a little bit of time to kill.</description></item><item><title>Grunt setup</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/11/grunt-setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/11/grunt-setup/</guid><description>This article might be helpful to anybody who satisfies the following criteria:
Wants to run Grunt On a Mac Running Linux through VirtualBox Using a shared folder for the directory you want to install packages If this describes your situation, you probably have run into errors installing the local version of Grunt through npm
The reason for these errors might be that your Shared Folder doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually support symlinks.</description></item><item><title>Pure-ftpd virtual users</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/10/pure-ftpd-virtual-users/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/10/pure-ftpd-virtual-users/</guid><description>Long ago I attempted to setup my first FTP daemon on linux. One point that constantly caused me issues was how to setup users.
The basic setup I wanted was for an FTP user to be able to login, upload some files and the web server to serve them. When I was first looking at this I was thinking in terms of real users. This issue with this was that the real user would have real file permissions.</description></item><item><title>i3 wm</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/10/i3-wm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/10/i3-wm/</guid><description>Had a nice play recently with the i3 wm for Linux.
It&amp;rsquo;s a really nice paradigm for working with when programming. It uses the same style of keyboard navigation as vim for moving around your windows.
The windows key can be bound as your modifier key and then used to navigate to a particular workspace (e.g. Windows + 2 to go to the browser workspace). Particular applications can be configured to open only on certain workspaces.</description></item><item><title>SSD upgrade MacBook Pro</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/09/ssd-upgrade-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/09/ssd-upgrade-macbook-pro/</guid><description>Tutorials I recently updated my hard drive on my MacBook Pro to an SSD drive. I used the following tutorials to do the upgrade, which was pretty stratightforward:
The second video is particularly interesting. You can purchase a cradle for another hard drive. This can be used either for you existing hard drive, or a second identical SSD that you can then put in RAID configuration.</description></item><item><title>Google Reader Replacement (follow up)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/09/google-reader-replacement-follow-up/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/09/google-reader-replacement-follow-up/</guid><description>I spent a bit of time today customising my RSSOwl setup to make it more to my liking. I now have it looking like this:
That&amp;rsquo;s one long reader with all my feeds. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did it.
Select View -&amp;gt; Layout -&amp;gt; Newspaper Deselect View -&amp;gt; Toolbars -&amp;gt; Feed Toolbar Deselect View -&amp;gt; Status Right Click Main Toolbar and select Customise Toolbar Delete everything except New, Update All, Mark Read, Mark All Read, Search (or whatever is your preference) Right Click Main Toolbar and select Lock Toolbar Click Search, do a search for all titles not containing something impossible (eg asjdlfjkasdfkdaj) Save search (I called mine &amp;ldquo;All News&amp;rdquo;) Select the newly created &amp;ldquo;All News&amp;rdquo; category from your feeds (More details on this here: http://tutorial.</description></item><item><title>Axure - Wireframing Application</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/05/axure-wireframing-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/05/axure-wireframing-application/</guid><description>I recently started using Axure as my primary wireframing application. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a couple of other solutions in the past, such as balsamiq and Adobe Illustrator.
There&amp;rsquo;s a good article here which discusses some of the other alternatives: http://www.creativebloq.com/wireframes/top-wireframing-tools-11121302
My own criteria for selection were:
No web apps While I love cloud based solutions for some stuff, for my core apps I loathe anything that requires connectivity to use. If I have my laptop, I should be able to do my work, regardless of whether I have access to the internet.</description></item><item><title>Google Reader Replacement</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/04/google-reader-replacement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/04/google-reader-replacement/</guid><description>Google Reader is going the way of the dodo. I am/was an active Reader user. Mostly from the browser while I had some spare minutes I would dip and read some of the latest news.
The news hast left me somewhat wary of online alternatives. There have been quite a few mentioned:
http://www.newsblur.com/ http://www.feedly.com/ http://www.netvibes.com/ https://www.pulse.me/ While all of these seem perfectly reasonable, it&amp;rsquo;s all coming back to the same issue for me.</description></item><item><title>Swift Keys</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/04/swift-keys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/04/swift-keys/</guid><description>I recently installed on my Galaxy S3 a new keyboard called Swift Keys. I&amp;rsquo;m amazed at how good it is. Ok, I can still type on a keyboard faster, but still it&amp;rsquo;s a marked improvement from other keyboards out there.
I have felt lately that whomever can find a way to make text input on a tablet/smartphone would go a long way to bridging the gap between the traditional PC and current hand held devices.</description></item><item><title>First Flare3D project</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/first-flare3d-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/first-flare3d-project/</guid><description>Where I work in Brando we got an opportunity recently to work on an interesting project.
The project was a website for Qatar based Agency 222. They wanted the site to have as it&amp;rsquo;s central point a 3D cube. While evaluating the project, it became apparent that the web has reached an interesting point in it&amp;rsquo;s relationship with 3D.
3D in the Browser Since the days when Director was one of the main web plugins for advanced multi-media projects there has been something of a dearth in 3D capable plugins for the web.</description></item><item><title>Something to be said for concentrating on one language</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/something-to-be-said-for-concentrating-on-one-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/something-to-be-said-for-concentrating-on-one-language/</guid><description>I recently have been thinking about some of the above I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in some corners I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in relation to how programmers should learn some different programming languages.
The accepted thinking seems to be that learning a couple of languages is advantageous to a developer because:
See different ways to solve problems View different tool sets Freshen things up, just in case you get bored Maybe force you to look at how you are doing things in a different light Keep you skill-set strong and up to date I&amp;rsquo;ve been finding recently though that learning a new programming for website development isn&amp;rsquo;t generally applicable.</description></item><item><title>One weekend with Ubuntu</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/one-weekend-with-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/one-weekend-with-ubuntu/</guid><description>I have an itch. This itch has been bothering me for probably ten years now.
I am drawn to idea of doing most of my work on Linux. Every year or so I attempt to scratch this itch to see if it&amp;rsquo;s finally possible.
Why do I want to move to Linux? Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve become conscious about where Microsoft and Apple seem to be taking the desktop experience. Closed Wall == Max Profit.</description></item><item><title>Facebook apps ahoy</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/12/facebook-apps-ahoy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/12/facebook-apps-ahoy/</guid><description>We recently finished up on a couple of facebook apps at Brando. The first, an app for Lifestyle Sports, gave me a chance to look further into the Wowza server and live streaming. The cam seems to be broadcasting though and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a few things about setup for this. I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with the results.
The first was for BUPI. It allowed the user to upload an image of their child, and then put them in a Christmas card.</description></item><item><title>Bess has pups</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/11/bess-has-pups/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/11/bess-has-pups/</guid><description>Quick update on Bess, she has now entered the stage of life of motherhood. The pups are fine and healthy, 4 boys. There&amp;rsquo;s something really cute about being followed by the pitter patter of 16 little paws when you go out the door.</description></item><item><title>Strobe Media Player</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/10/strobe-media-player/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/10/strobe-media-player/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of flash video players over the years. Too many.
Some had custom interfaces, some used the default flash video component. Others were completely custom, managing the stream events and displaying the video in the vanilla video component. Then Dave came to me with the OSMF Strobe Media Playback component.
We had tried the JW Player a couple of times before, but found the per domain price a little excessive outside of large clients.</description></item><item><title>Wordpress wp_nav_menu output class when menu item has children</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/09/wordpress-wp_nav_menu-output-class-when-menu-item-has-children/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/09/wordpress-wp_nav_menu-output-class-when-menu-item-has-children/</guid><description>I recently wanted to insert a class for the case where a menu item has children in Wordpress. There doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be any option to do this in wp_nav_menu function, so I started doing some research.
I found out from this article how to add a &amp;lsquo;last-menu-item&amp;rsquo; css class.
This doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite work for what I wanted though, because the returned data object from Wordpress doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell you if the current node has children.</description></item><item><title>Tour De Picnic</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/09/tour-de-picnic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/09/tour-de-picnic/</guid><description>Ronan Murphy, Dave Clarke, David Byrne and I recently put a site live for Tour De Picnic. This is a charity cycle to the Electric Picnic festival in Stradbally in aid of Temple Street Hospital. Ronan was doing the cycle and we decided it would be nice to track him on his journey.
Thus was born a website that used an iphone, a handy iPhone app called SendLocation, a little lamp coding, google maps api and some html/css/javascript to update Ronans location throughout the trip.</description></item><item><title>Baby steps with Python</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/06/baby-steps-with-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/06/baby-steps-with-python/</guid><description>Started out playing around with Python as a scripting tool. Have to say, it really is a neat mix of the kinda power and libraries I&amp;rsquo;m used to with Perl and the flexibility of a pure scripting language.
Just for a giggle, I decided to re-write my C# backup script to backup some of my mac folders. Most of the language I&amp;rsquo;m still getting my head around. 4 times out of ten, each line gets a semi-colon.</description></item><item><title>Got a new bike</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/05/got-a-new-bike/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2011/05/got-a-new-bike/</guid><description>Picked up a 07 Honda Hornet 600F a week ago. Seem to be a really nice bike to ride with puck of power in just about any gear.</description></item><item><title>Be The Difference gets a Cannes Lion and a One Show merit</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/07/be-the-difference-gets-a-cannes-lion-and-a-one-show-merit-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/07/be-the-difference-gets-a-cannes-lion-and-a-one-show-merit-2/</guid><description>Be The Difference 2010 has picked up a one show merit and a cannes lion. Congrats to all the lads, well done.</description></item><item><title>Kentico Smart Search</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/06/kentico-smart-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/06/kentico-smart-search/</guid><description>Recently started work on a new website. We&amp;rsquo;re using the Kentico CMS, and came across the following while building some search based functionality: http://www.kentico.com/Docs/DevGuide/smart_search_overview.htm
The lads have integrated their system with a C# port of the lucene search engine library. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far, this gives developers really powerful search and sorting options. A summary of some these options can be found here http://lucene.apache.org/java/2_1_0/queryparsersyntax.html.
Like I say, I&amp;rsquo;ve only started on this, and will update this post when the project is finished.</description></item><item><title>Sweet sweet bronze</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/04/sweet-sweet-bronze/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2010/04/sweet-sweet-bronze/</guid><description>An MSN takeover Brando did for O2 last year picked up a bronze at the ICAD awards last week. Congrats to all at Brando</description></item><item><title>Lists of lists</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/10/lists-of-lists/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/10/lists-of-lists/</guid><description>In the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve run into quite a few &amp;lsquo;list&amp;rsquo; site. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just throw a few on the page here see if can build up a list of lists. So, here we go:
http://www.engrish.com http://failblog.org http://www.headsethotties.com/ http://awkwardfamilyphotos.com/ http://www.bash.org http://www.truthbank.ie</description></item><item><title>Be The Difference gets a shark</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/09/be-the-difference-gets-a-shark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/09/be-the-difference-gets-a-shark/</guid><description>Congrats to Brad, Alan, Dave and the whole team who worked on www.bethedifference.ie for the recent bronze kinsale shark win for Brando.</description></item><item><title>Daily filing</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/08/daily-filing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/08/daily-filing/</guid><description>A few years ago I was in my Boss' office in Interactve Services. He was showing me something on his computer, and I saw that his filing system was a system of folders named according to the date. So he never had a build up of files in one particular place.
I took this system on-board and modified it to my needs, and just thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it here. I have a folder on the desktop called &amp;ldquo;_today&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Twitter – First Impressions</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/07/twitter-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/07/twitter-first-impressions/</guid><description>Site implementation I recently got set up on Twitter. I&amp;rsquo;ve been hearing about it and scuttling around it for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ll preface this by saying that I&amp;rsquo;ve only been using this for a short while, so I may just not have found some stuff out. So far I&amp;rsquo;m digging it. The concept is very simple, sms for web. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Create a user and post a message in 140 characters.</description></item><item><title>Process Explorer</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/05/process-explorer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/05/process-explorer/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a bit more information than Task Manger manager provides, Process Explorer, also from Microsoft may be the answer. With it you can view your processess in a hierarchical tree, find out what processess are safe and find out which process is running a particular window.
These are just a few of the capabilities, and you can configure it to run instead of Task Manager at the click of a button.</description></item><item><title>Can you handle the truth?</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/05/can-you-handle-the-truth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/05/can-you-handle-the-truth/</guid><description>Brando recently completed work on the truthbank for Rabodirect. The purpose of this campaign was to emphasise the point that Rabo is a truthful bank. So, at the center of a campaign that utilised print/tv/radio/online we had a website dedicated to lifes truths. You can see the site here and judge for yourself.</description></item><item><title>Blanchardstown, handy distance from everywhere in Ireland?</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/04/blanchardstown-handy-distance-from-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/04/blanchardstown-handy-distance-from-everywhere/</guid><description>After trying out a few of the Irish online shops for our equipment, I settled on Komplett about a year ago. They have good prices, a comprehensive selection and an easily navigable website. All happy out. Not quite.
A while ago, they changed their online delivery options, which I think is very confusing. I needed to purchase a SATA hard drive. Having located the item on their site, I went to purchase it.</description></item><item><title>Bess one year on</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/04/bess-one-year-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/04/bess-one-year-on/</guid><description>Bess has grown a little bit from the pup who arrived about the year ago. She is now a near fully grown German Shepard.</description></item><item><title>Be The Difference</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/03/be-the-difference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/03/be-the-difference/</guid><description>Brando finished up the online execution of the be the difference campaign for O2, offering the unique opportunity to have your name placed on an Irish players jersey during the Ireland vs England,Scotland and Wales games. You can find out more about the campaign at the Brando blog here.
Visit the campaign site.</description></item><item><title>AS3 Frosty Toes</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/02/as3-frosty-toes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/02/as3-frosty-toes/</guid><description>I recently dipped my toes into the Actionscript 3 toes. This is quite a readjustment from the experience of the past 7/8 years of traditional actionscript development. I was somewhat prepared after having done a lot of projects with Object Oriented programming languages. Specifically Java and C# (VB sucks balls). I, along with most actionscript developers, tried to con ourselves that first abusing the prototype property and then the abortive actionscript 2 was actually OOP.</description></item><item><title>My 2nd Bike</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/01/new-bike-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/01/new-bike-2/</guid><description>I got a new bike, a Honda Hornet 250. It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely little bike, Japanese import because this model was never released outside Japan. It redlines at 16,000 RPM and can reach up to 180 Km/h. I bought it at Tallaght Superbikes and Autos. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to ride and is perfect for jinking in and out of traffic. I bought because while the cbf 250 is a great starter bike, it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it outside the city.</description></item><item><title>My entry for 25 lines</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/my-entry-for-25-lines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/my-entry-for-25-lines/</guid><description>To maintain my interest in this competition, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I&amp;rsquo;d put in my own entry (below). It&amp;rsquo;s an implementation of the logistic map. This is a great little equation, which can be used to describe population growth. The most interesting thing about it, is that certain values cause it to display random (chaotic) behavious. Not the most exciting thing in the world to most, but&amp;hellip;
//</description></item><item><title>25 lines challenge</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/25-lines-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/25-lines-challenge/</guid><description>The 25 lines of code challenge is on!!
http://www.25lines.com/</description></item><item><title>O2 Blueroom goes live</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/o2-blueroom-goes-live/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/o2-blueroom-goes-live/</guid><description>Recently, Brando went live with the O2 Blueroom site, an area for discussing and finding out information about music. It is also linked in with the new The O2 venue (the old point). You can also sign up for priority tickets, which is handy.</description></item><item><title>Interesting little browser feature</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/10/interesting-little-browser-feature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/10/interesting-little-browser-feature/</guid><description>Ever wanted to edit any page in place. Well you always could apparently. Simply enter the following in IE or Firefox and you can edit content in place. Handy for mocking up web pages.
javascript:document.body.contentEditable='true'; document.designMode='on'; void 0</description></item><item><title>New Brando Site</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/10/new-brando-site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/10/new-brando-site/</guid><description>After months of attempts, we finally got around to updating the Brando site. We&amp;rsquo;ve tried to simplify it as much as possible. Click the image below to view it.</description></item><item><title>Bizarre line of questioning</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/06/bizarre-line-of-questioning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/06/bizarre-line-of-questioning/</guid><description>Never one to think of myself as a p.c. nazi, I have to say I was a little taken aback by a question asked of me by the FAI. I was filling out a form for my nephew so he could go to a summer soccer camp. The idea is an excellent one, and definitley helps get children out and about during the summer months. But while going through the registration process, I noticed this:</description></item><item><title>Fuck it!!!, we'll do it live</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/05/fuck-it-well-do-it-live/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/05/fuck-it-well-do-it-live/</guid><description>American anchorman loses it&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Direct Your Own Movie</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/05/direct-your-own-movie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/05/direct-your-own-movie/</guid><description>Brando just finished up this piece for O2. It was developed by Darran Morris.</description></item><item><title>Flash Player bug database</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/04/flash-player-bug-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/04/flash-player-bug-database/</guid><description>Adobe has made the bug database for the flash player public. Its well worth a look if you&amp;rsquo;ve got something that should be working but isn&amp;rsquo;t.
https://bugs.adobe.com/jira/browse/FP</description></item><item><title>Don't mess with Bess</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/04/dont-mess-with-bess/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/04/dont-mess-with-bess/</guid><description>New pooch here as well. For some reason the bitch is called Bess. She arrived as a puppy and after a few weeks is now massive.</description></item><item><title>New bike</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/04/new-bike/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/04/new-bike/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently moved from four wheels back down to two :o
I got a Honda CBF 250. It&amp;rsquo;s going well, enjoying learning something new. And having an excuse to wear leathers is just the icing on the cake.</description></item><item><title>MacBook + Coffee = tears</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/macbook-coffee-tears/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/macbook-coffee-tears/</guid><description>We had a coffee spillage here, resulting in a sad macbook. Two little things to come out of it though:
Taking hard drives out of mac books is actually relatively painless. It merely involves 3 screws, a likkle screwdriver and an L-plate behind the battery. A little external hard drive case (nicely provided by Darran) can save a lot of bother. Simply remove the hard drive, insert it into the case, plug into another computer and with any luck your hard drive is up and running</description></item><item><title>Make your own ad</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/make-your-own-ad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/make-your-own-ad/</guid><description>We recently finished a nice piece of work for O2. This is an application which allows the user to upload a photo, cut out a section, and then put it in an ad. Then the user can send his creation to his mates, opportunities for hilarity abound.
You can view it here.</description></item><item><title>_lockroot</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/_lockroot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/_lockroot/</guid><description>Found a great little variable in flash on Friday, _lockroot. It makes every reference to _root in a movie refer to its own Stage, no matter what movie loads it in. Theres more here.</description></item><item><title>Design and the elastic mind</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/design-and-the-elastic-mind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/design-and-the-elastic-mind/</guid><description>Interesting site http://www.moma.org/exhibitions/2008/elasticmind/</description></item><item><title>World at night</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/world-at-night/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/world-at-night/</guid><description>Cool image of the world at night. Click the image to see it at full size. You can get the google gadget here</description></item><item><title>IRC Chats</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/irc-chats/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/irc-chats/</guid><description>Theres a log here of funny irc chats. Some of my favorites are:
Sharing a bit too much in biology The importance of proof-reading Worst night out ever Timing is everything</description></item><item><title>Oh me of little faith</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/oh-me-of-little-faith/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/oh-me-of-little-faith/</guid><description>Not two days after I posted with my Apple MacBook problem the good people at apple have released a fix, Huzzah</description></item><item><title>MacBook Pro Leopard upgrade problem</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/macbook-pro-leopard-upgrade-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/macbook-pro-leopard-upgrade-problem/</guid><description>Nice one, upgraded to Mac OS X Leopard recently. All very snazzy and apple like, icons flying from this angle, little transitions everywhere. Recently though, when I go to type I get a big fat nothing on the screen. Theres more info here at apple insider about the mysterious unresponsive keyboard problem.</description></item><item><title>Christmas carousel</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/christmas-carousel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/christmas-carousel/</guid><description>Just finished work on our latest piece for O2. Designed by Ray Doyle, it&amp;rsquo;s a carousel displaying the latest phones in the O2 range. Additionally, there is the ability to send a hint to your nearest and dearest about what phone you&amp;rsquo;d like for christmas.
The phones are displayed in a carousel, and you can also send greeting cards. Click here to take a look.</description></item><item><title>Hard disk failure</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/hard-disk-failure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/hard-disk-failure/</guid><description>My hard drive at work crapped out on Tuesday, sonofab****
Got onto the oh so nice people at Dell, excellent customer service. Drive had more errors than a dyslexic at a spelling bee. Managed to get it booted up again though and got some stuff off it. Then Dell sent out a replacement drive, nice.
Learned a valuable lesson. The two most important locations to back up if you use Thunderbird and Firefox:</description></item><item><title>Multiple phpBB2 forums</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/multiple-phpbb2-forums/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/multiple-phpbb2-forums/</guid><description>Spent an inordinate amount of time solving a problem last week. A site with multiple forums, forums were hosted inside an iframe (but under the same domain).
Problem: trying to go into administration panel of the board would either crash the browser or cause an internal server error. Hmmph.
Solution: Auto cookies, nice likkle script which suggested the right settings for me. http://www.phpbb.com/community/viewtopic.php?t=228741</description></item><item><title>Sifr, nummy fonts accross the web</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/sifr-nummy-fonts-accross-the-web/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/12/sifr-nummy-fonts-accross-the-web/</guid><description>Combining javascript, css, xhtml and flash, this handy little script allows you to safely embed non standard fonts and still achieve w3c compatibility. Nice.
http://www.mikeindustries.com/sifr</description></item><item><title>Rusty the narcoleptic dog</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/08/hello-world-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2007/08/hello-world-2/</guid><description>Probably the funniest video on the internet</description></item></channel></rss>