<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on trootski</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on trootski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trootski.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lovin Miniflux</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2025/09/lovin-miniflux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2025/09/lovin-miniflux/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve made some references in the past to my attempts over the years to replace &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Reader">Google Reader&lt;/a>. Released in 2005 the functionality it offered was convenient. I have tried multiple times applications to replace this, but none offered the same level of simplicity. I love RSS as a concept because it empowers open decentralised distribution. The consumer gets to control the feeds they consume. You choose your feeds. As long as you&amp;rsquo;re just sorting by date there is no ‘algorithm&amp;rsquo; nudging you in one direction or another.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A year of the Linux desktop</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2024/11/longest-linux-run-yet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2024/11/longest-linux-run-yet/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have previously had multiple forays into Linux as my main desktop. This has generally ended with a return to macOS at some point for one reason or another. This pattern has recently repeated itself. However, I think it’s worth recording that this time the switch back was not due to any irreconcilable issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pure-ftpd virtual users</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/10/pure-ftpd-virtual-users/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/10/pure-ftpd-virtual-users/</guid><description>Long ago I attempted to setup my first FTP daemon on linux. One point that constantly caused me issues was how to setup users.
The basic setup I wanted was for an FTP user to be able to login, upload some files and the web server to serve them. When I was first looking at this I was thinking in terms of real users. This issue with this was that the real user would have real file permissions.</description></item><item><title>i3 wm</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/10/i3-wm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/10/i3-wm/</guid><description>Had a nice play recently with the i3 wm for Linux.
It&amp;rsquo;s a really nice paradigm for working with when programming. It uses the same style of keyboard navigation as vim for moving around your windows.
The windows key can be bound as your modifier key and then used to navigate to a particular workspace (e.g. Windows + 2 to go to the browser workspace). Particular applications can be configured to open only on certain workspaces.</description></item><item><title>One weekend with Ubuntu</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/03/one-weekend-with-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/03/one-weekend-with-ubuntu/</guid><description>I have an itch. This itch has been bothering me for probably ten years now.
I am drawn to idea of doing most of my work on Linux. Every year or so I attempt to scratch this itch to see if it&amp;rsquo;s finally possible.
Why do I want to move to Linux? Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve become conscious about where Microsoft and Apple seem to be taking the desktop experience. Closed Wall == Max Profit.</description></item></channel></rss>