<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Engineering on trootski</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/software-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Software Engineering on trootski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Flare3D project</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/first-flare3d-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/first-flare3d-project/</guid><description>Where I work in Brando we got an opportunity recently to work on an interesting project.
The project was a website for Qatar based Agency 222. They wanted the site to have as it&amp;rsquo;s central point a 3D cube. While evaluating the project, it became apparent that the web has reached an interesting point in it&amp;rsquo;s relationship with 3D.
3D in the Browser Since the days when Director was one of the main web plugins for advanced multi-media projects there has been something of a dearth in 3D capable plugins for the web.</description></item><item><title>Something to be said for concentrating on one language</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/something-to-be-said-for-concentrating-on-one-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2013/03/something-to-be-said-for-concentrating-on-one-language/</guid><description>I recently have been thinking about some of the above I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in some corners I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in relation to how programmers should learn some different programming languages.
The accepted thinking seems to be that learning a couple of languages is advantageous to a developer because:
See different ways to solve problems View different tool sets Freshen things up, just in case you get bored Maybe force you to look at how you are doing things in a different light Keep you skill-set strong and up to date I&amp;rsquo;ve been finding recently though that learning a new programming for website development isn&amp;rsquo;t generally applicable.</description></item><item><title>Daily filing</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/08/daily-filing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/08/daily-filing/</guid><description>A few years ago I was in my Boss&amp;rsquo; office in Interactve Services. He was showing me something on his computer, and I saw that his filing system was a system of folders named according to the date. So he never had a build up of files in one particular place.
I took this system on-board and modified it to my needs, and just thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it here. I have a folder on the desktop called &amp;ldquo;_today&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>AS3 Frosty Toes</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/02/as3-frosty-toes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/02/as3-frosty-toes/</guid><description>I recently dipped my toes into the Actionscript 3 toes. This is quite a readjustment from the experience of the past 7/8 years of traditional actionscript development. I was somewhat prepared after having done a lot of projects with Object Oriented programming languages. Specifically Java and C# (VB sucks balls). I, along with most actionscript developers, tried to con ourselves that first abusing the prototype property and then the abortive actionscript 2 was actually OOP.</description></item><item><title>My entry for 25 lines</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/my-entry-for-25-lines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/my-entry-for-25-lines/</guid><description>To maintain my interest in this competition, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I&amp;rsquo;d put in my own entry (below). It&amp;rsquo;s an implementation of the logistic map. This is a great little equation, which can be used to describe population growth. The most interesting thing about it, is that certain values cause it to display random (chaotic) behavious. Not the most exciting thing in the world to most, but&amp;hellip;
//</description></item><item><title>25 lines challenge</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/25-lines-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/11/25-lines-challenge/</guid><description>The 25 lines of code challenge is on!!
http://www.25lines.com/</description></item><item><title>_lockroot</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/_lockroot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/_lockroot/</guid><description>Found a great little variable in flash on Friday, _lockroot. It makes every reference to _root in a movie refer to its own Stage, no matter what movie loads it in. Theres more here.</description></item><item><title>Design and the elastic mind</title><link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/design-and-the-elastic-mind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/03/design-and-the-elastic-mind/</guid><description>Interesting site http://www.moma.org/exhibitions/2008/elasticmind/</description></item></channel></rss>