<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Software Engineering on trootski</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/tags/software-engineering/</link><description>Recent content in Software Engineering on trootski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trootski.github.io/tags/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What I wished I'd known before working with Apache Camel</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2021/12/what-i-wished-id-known-before-working-with-apache-camel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2021/12/what-i-wished-id-known-before-working-with-apache-camel/</guid><description>I recently started working on an Apache Camel project at work. The application in question would, I imagine, have been an atypical use case for Apache Camel. It was used primarily for the DSL definition of a series of RESTful calls to dependent services. These routes were leveraged by the application’s controller layer.
My approach at the beginning and my approach by the end were pretty different.
Unless stated the below are examples are taken from the Apache Camel Wish I&amp;rsquo;d Known sample code on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Bond Project</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2021/01/bond-project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2021/01/bond-project/</guid><description>While looking at various microservice patterns I found I wanted a playground for playing with components of a microservice based system in isolation.
Coincidentally, in the halcyon days of winter 2019 I got an idea to binge all the James Bond films. Over the years I had seen them all. I generally watched them on television but never in any order and usually having missed the start. After having re-watched one of the movies I wrote down a very short hot take on each film.</description></item><item><title>Spring Handle Constraint Violation</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2020/12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2020/12/</guid><description>My team recently had a requirement to build a persistence mechanism that had a unique constraint on a combination of columns. It needed to behave in an idempotent manner. If the same request was received to created an entity multiple times it would simply respond that the items existed. I spent a considerable amount of effort researching a solution and wound up with something immeasurably simpler than some of my early stabs at it.</description></item><item><title>Outlook Kung-Fu</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2015/11/outlook-kung-fu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2015/11/outlook-kung-fu/</guid><description>While in the process of doing some HTML emails recently I had some issues with Outlook.
Stinky, sneaky Outlook. I learned a few little techniques though that are worth sharing.
Only show this on Outlook First and foremost, only show the content between the conditionals on Outlook.
&amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;!--\[if gte mso 9\]&amp;amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;/pre&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;only on outlook&amp;#34;&amp;amp;amp;gt;&amp;amp;amp;lt;/div&amp;amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;amp;amp;lt;!\[endif\]--&amp;amp;amp;amp;gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t show this on Outlook (v1) Anything with the style mso-hide: all will be hidden on Outlook.</description></item><item><title>Migrate Wordpress Database</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2015/09/migrate-wordpress-database/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2015/09/migrate-wordpress-database/</guid><description>I recently found the WP-CLI library and have been investigating ways I can integrate it into my workflow. I should note here that we use shared hosting extensively. Ideally the preferred solution would be to use a true migration tool. This is not always possible with shared hosting.
To use the tool the following commands would be issued:
migrate_wordpress.sh dev production This command would pull the latest version of the wordpress database from the production server.</description></item><item><title>First Flare3D project</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/03/first-flare3d-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/03/first-flare3d-project/</guid><description>Where I work in Brando we got an opportunity recently to work on an interesting project.
The project was a website for Qatar based Agency 222. They wanted the site to have as it&amp;rsquo;s central point a 3D cube. While evaluating the project, it became apparent that the web has reached an interesting point in it&amp;rsquo;s relationship with 3D.
3D in the Browser Since the days when Director was one of the main web plugins for advanced multi-media projects there has been something of a dearth in 3D capable plugins for the web.</description></item><item><title>Something to be said for concentrating on one language</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/03/something-to-be-said-for-concentrating-on-one-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/03/something-to-be-said-for-concentrating-on-one-language/</guid><description>I recently have been thinking about some of the above I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in some corners I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in relation to how programmers should learn some different programming languages.
The accepted thinking seems to be that learning a couple of languages is advantageous to a developer because:
See different ways to solve problems View different tool sets Freshen things up, just in case you get bored Maybe force you to look at how you are doing things in a different light Keep you skill-set strong and up to date I&amp;rsquo;ve been finding recently though that learning a new programming for website development isn&amp;rsquo;t generally applicable.</description></item><item><title>Strobe Media Player</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/10/strobe-media-player/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/10/strobe-media-player/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of flash video players over the years. Too many.
Some had custom interfaces, some used the default flash video component. Others were completely custom, managing the stream events and displaying the video in the vanilla video component. Then Dave came to me with the OSMF Strobe Media Playback component.
We had tried the JW Player a couple of times before, but found the per domain price a little excessive outside of large clients.</description></item><item><title>Wordpress wp_nav_menu output class when menu item has children</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/09/wordpress-wp_nav_menu-output-class-when-menu-item-has-children/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/09/wordpress-wp_nav_menu-output-class-when-menu-item-has-children/</guid><description>I recently wanted to insert a class for the case where a menu item has children in Wordpress. There doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be any option to do this in wp_nav_menu function, so I started doing some research.
I found out from this article how to add a &amp;rsquo;last-menu-item&amp;rsquo; css class.
This doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite work for what I wanted though, because the returned data object from Wordpress doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell you if the current node has children.</description></item><item><title>Tour De Picnic</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/09/tour-de-picnic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/09/tour-de-picnic/</guid><description>Ronan Murphy, Dave Clarke, David Byrne and I recently put a site live for Tour De Picnic. This is a charity cycle to the Electric Picnic festival in Stradbally in aid of Temple Street Hospital. Ronan was doing the cycle and we decided it would be nice to track him on his journey.
Thus was born a website that used an iphone, a handy iPhone app called SendLocation, a little lamp coding, google maps api and some html/css/javascript to update Ronans location throughout the trip.</description></item><item><title>Baby steps with Python</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/06/baby-steps-with-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/06/baby-steps-with-python/</guid><description>Started out playing around with Python as a scripting tool. Have to say, it really is a neat mix of the kinda power and libraries I&amp;rsquo;m used to with Perl and the flexibility of a pure scripting language.
Just for a giggle, I decided to re-write my C# backup script to backup some of my mac folders. Most of the language I&amp;rsquo;m still getting my head around. 4 times out of ten, each line gets a semi-colon.</description></item><item><title>Kentico Smart Search</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2010/06/kentico-smart-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2010/06/kentico-smart-search/</guid><description>Recently started work on a new website. We&amp;rsquo;re using the Kentico CMS, and came across the following while building some search based functionality: http://www.kentico.com/Docs/DevGuide/smart_search_overview.htm
The lads have integrated their system with a C# port of the lucene search engine library. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far, this gives developers really powerful search and sorting options. A summary of some these options can be found here http://lucene.apache.org/java/2_1_0/queryparsersyntax.html.
Like I say, I&amp;rsquo;ve only started on this, and will update this post when the project is finished.</description></item><item><title>Daily filing</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/08/daily-filing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/08/daily-filing/</guid><description>A few years ago I was in my Boss&amp;rsquo; office in Interactve Services. He was showing me something on his computer, and I saw that his filing system was a system of folders named according to the date. So he never had a build up of files in one particular place.
I took this system on-board and modified it to my needs, and just thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it here. I have a folder on the desktop called &amp;ldquo;_today&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>AS3 Frosty Toes</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/02/as3-frosty-toes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/02/as3-frosty-toes/</guid><description>I recently dipped my toes into the Actionscript 3 toes. This is quite a readjustment from the experience of the past 7/8 years of traditional actionscript development. I was somewhat prepared after having done a lot of projects with Object Oriented programming languages. Specifically Java and C# (VB sucks balls). I, along with most actionscript developers, tried to con ourselves that first abusing the prototype property and then the abortive actionscript 2 was actually OOP.</description></item><item><title>My entry for 25 lines</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/11/my-entry-for-25-lines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/11/my-entry-for-25-lines/</guid><description>To maintain my interest in this competition, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I&amp;rsquo;d put in my own entry (below). It&amp;rsquo;s an implementation of the logistic map. This is a great little equation, which can be used to describe population growth. The most interesting thing about it, is that certain values cause it to display random (chaotic) behavious. Not the most exciting thing in the world to most, but&amp;hellip;
//</description></item><item><title>25 lines challenge</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/11/25-lines-challenge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/11/25-lines-challenge/</guid><description>The 25 lines of code challenge is on!!
http://www.25lines.com/</description></item><item><title>_lockroot</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/03/_lockroot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/03/_lockroot/</guid><description>Found a great little variable in flash on Friday, _lockroot. It makes every reference to _root in a movie refer to its own Stage, no matter what movie loads it in. Theres more here.</description></item></channel></rss>