<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Work on trootski</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/tags/work/</link><description>Recent content in Work on trootski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trootski.github.io/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Facebook apps ahoy</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/12/facebook-apps-ahoy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/12/facebook-apps-ahoy/</guid><description>We recently finished up on a couple of facebook apps at Brando. The first, an app for Lifestyle Sports, gave me a chance to look further into the Wowza server and live streaming. The cam seems to be broadcasting though and I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a few things about setup for this. I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with the results.
The first was for BUPI. It allowed the user to upload an image of their child, and then put them in a Christmas card.</description></item><item><title>Strobe Media Player</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/10/strobe-media-player/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/10/strobe-media-player/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot of flash video players over the years. Too many.
Some had custom interfaces, some used the default flash video component. Others were completely custom, managing the stream events and displaying the video in the vanilla video component. Then Dave came to me with the OSMF Strobe Media Playback component.
We had tried the JW Player a couple of times before, but found the per domain price a little excessive outside of large clients.</description></item><item><title>Wordpress wp_nav_menu output class when menu item has children</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/09/wordpress-wp_nav_menu-output-class-when-menu-item-has-children/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/09/wordpress-wp_nav_menu-output-class-when-menu-item-has-children/</guid><description>I recently wanted to insert a class for the case where a menu item has children in Wordpress. There doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be any option to do this in wp_nav_menu function, so I started doing some research.
I found out from this article how to add a &amp;rsquo;last-menu-item&amp;rsquo; css class.
This doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite work for what I wanted though, because the returned data object from Wordpress doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell you if the current node has children.</description></item><item><title>Be The Difference gets a Cannes Lion and a One Show merit</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2010/07/be-the-difference-gets-a-cannes-lion-and-a-one-show-merit-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2010/07/be-the-difference-gets-a-cannes-lion-and-a-one-show-merit-2/</guid><description>Be The Difference 2010 has picked up a one show merit and a cannes lion. Congrats to all the lads, well done.</description></item><item><title>Kentico Smart Search</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2010/06/kentico-smart-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2010/06/kentico-smart-search/</guid><description>Recently started work on a new website. We&amp;rsquo;re using the Kentico CMS, and came across the following while building some search based functionality: http://www.kentico.com/Docs/DevGuide/smart_search_overview.htm
The lads have integrated their system with a C# port of the lucene search engine library. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far, this gives developers really powerful search and sorting options. A summary of some these options can be found here http://lucene.apache.org/java/2_1_0/queryparsersyntax.html.
Like I say, I&amp;rsquo;ve only started on this, and will update this post when the project is finished.</description></item><item><title>Sweet sweet bronze</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2010/04/sweet-sweet-bronze/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2010/04/sweet-sweet-bronze/</guid><description>An MSN takeover Brando did for O2 last year picked up a bronze at the ICAD awards last week. Congrats to all at Brando</description></item><item><title>Be The Difference gets a shark</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/09/be-the-difference-gets-a-shark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/09/be-the-difference-gets-a-shark/</guid><description>Congrats to Brad, Alan, Dave and the whole team who worked on www.bethedifference.ie for the recent bronze kinsale shark win for Brando.</description></item><item><title>Can you handle the truth?</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/05/can-you-handle-the-truth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/05/can-you-handle-the-truth/</guid><description>Brando recently completed work on the truthbank for Rabodirect. The purpose of this campaign was to emphasise the point that Rabo is a truthful bank. So, at the center of a campaign that utilised print/tv/radio/online we had a website dedicated to lifes truths. You can see the site here and judge for yourself.</description></item><item><title>Be The Difference</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/03/be-the-difference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/03/be-the-difference/</guid><description>Brando finished up the online execution of the be the difference campaign for O2, offering the unique opportunity to have your name placed on an Irish players jersey during the Ireland vs England,Scotland and Wales games. You can find out more about the campaign at the Brando blog here.
Visit the campaign site.</description></item><item><title>O2 Blueroom goes live</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/11/o2-blueroom-goes-live/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/11/o2-blueroom-goes-live/</guid><description>Recently, Brando went live with the O2 Blueroom site, an area for discussing and finding out information about music. It is also linked in with the new The O2 venue (the old point). You can also sign up for priority tickets, which is handy.</description></item><item><title>New Brando Site</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/10/new-brando-site/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/10/new-brando-site/</guid><description>After months of attempts, we finally got around to updating the Brando site. We&amp;rsquo;ve tried to simplify it as much as possible. Click the image below to view it.</description></item><item><title>Direct Your Own Movie</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/05/direct-your-own-movie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/05/direct-your-own-movie/</guid><description>Brando just finished up this piece for O2. It was developed by Darran Morris.</description></item><item><title>Make your own ad</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/03/make-your-own-ad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/03/make-your-own-ad/</guid><description>We recently finished a nice piece of work for O2. This is an application which allows the user to upload a photo, cut out a section, and then put it in an ad. Then the user can send his creation to his mates, opportunities for hilarity abound.
You can view it here.</description></item><item><title>Christmas carousel</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2007/12/christmas-carousel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2007/12/christmas-carousel/</guid><description>Just finished work on our latest piece for O2. Designed by Ray Doyle, it&amp;rsquo;s a carousel displaying the latest phones in the O2 range. Additionally, there is the ability to send a hint to your nearest and dearest about what phone you&amp;rsquo;d like for christmas.
The phones are displayed in a carousel, and you can also send greeting cards. Click here to take a look.</description></item><item><title>Multiple phpBB2 forums</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2007/12/multiple-phpbb2-forums/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2007/12/multiple-phpbb2-forums/</guid><description>Spent an inordinate amount of time solving a problem last week. A site with multiple forums, forums were hosted inside an iframe (but under the same domain).
Problem: trying to go into administration panel of the board would either crash the browser or cause an internal server error. Hmmph.
Solution: Auto cookies, nice likkle script which suggested the right settings for me. http://www.phpbb.com/community/viewtopic.php?t=228741</description></item><item><title>Sifr, nummy fonts accross the web</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2007/12/sifr-nummy-fonts-accross-the-web/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2007/12/sifr-nummy-fonts-accross-the-web/</guid><description>Combining javascript, css, xhtml and flash, this handy little script allows you to safely embed non standard fonts and still achieve w3c compatibility. Nice.
http://www.mikeindustries.com/sifr</description></item></channel></rss>