<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on trootski</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on trootski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trootski.github.io/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Acer V5-122P display driver issue</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2019/03/acer-v5-122p-display-driver-issue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2019/03/acer-v5-122p-display-driver-issue/</guid><description>I had a rather disappointing experience recently with an Acer laptop that I&amp;rsquo;d like to make a note of. I think the crux of the issue is a difference between the latest driver available and the best driver for a machine.
The details are that the laptop is an Acer Aspire V5-122P. It is a cheap and cheerful laptop that I purchased for the following reasons:
Backup machine in case my daily driver broke down, Low powered machine to test performance of websites, Laptop I could take travelling without undue stress as to it&amp;rsquo;s wellbeing.</description></item><item><title>New Rig</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2014/01/new-rig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2014/01/new-rig/</guid><description>As a sort of follow up to the article here I decided to continue to attempt to scratch my Linux itch.
Reasoning that maybe virtual machines aren&amp;rsquo;t a fair reflection of a system&amp;rsquo;s capabilities I went and bought a little netbook. I went for a little Acer Aspire in the January sales. This is a relatively cheap model, but it was the Christmas break so I had a little bit of time to kill.</description></item><item><title>SSD upgrade MacBook Pro</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/09/ssd-upgrade-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2013/09/ssd-upgrade-macbook-pro/</guid><description>Tutorials I recently updated my hard drive on my MacBook Pro to an SSD drive. I used the following tutorials to do the upgrade, which was pretty stratightforward:
The second video is particularly interesting. You can purchase a cradle for another hard drive. This can be used either for you existing hard drive, or a second identical SSD that you can then put in RAID configuration.</description></item><item><title>MacBook + Coffee = tears</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/03/macbook-coffee-tears/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/03/macbook-coffee-tears/</guid><description>We had a coffee spillage here, resulting in a sad macbook. Two little things to come out of it though:
Taking hard drives out of mac books is actually relatively painless. It merely involves 3 screws, a likkle screwdriver and an L-plate behind the battery. A little external hard drive case (nicely provided by Darran) can save a lot of bother. Simply remove the hard drive, insert it into the case, plug into another computer and with any luck your hard drive is up and running</description></item></channel></rss>