<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on trootski</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on trootski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trootski.github.io/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bess has pups</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/11/bess-has-pups/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/11/bess-has-pups/</guid><description>Quick update on Bess, she has now entered the stage of life of motherhood. The pups are fine and healthy, 4 boys. There&amp;rsquo;s something really cute about being followed by the pitter patter of 16 little paws when you go out the door.</description></item><item><title>Tour De Picnic</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/09/tour-de-picnic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/09/tour-de-picnic/</guid><description>Ronan Murphy, Dave Clarke, David Byrne and I recently put a site live for Tour De Picnic. This is a charity cycle to the Electric Picnic festival in Stradbally in aid of Temple Street Hospital. Ronan was doing the cycle and we decided it would be nice to track him on his journey.
Thus was born a website that used an iphone, a handy iPhone app called SendLocation, a little lamp coding, google maps api and some html/css/javascript to update Ronans location throughout the trip.</description></item><item><title>Got a new bike</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/05/got-a-new-bike/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2011/05/got-a-new-bike/</guid><description>Picked up a 07 Honda Hornet 600F a week ago. Seem to be a really nice bike to ride with puck of power in just about any gear.</description></item><item><title>Blanchardstown, handy distance from everywhere in Ireland?</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/04/blanchardstown-handy-distance-from-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/04/blanchardstown-handy-distance-from-everywhere/</guid><description>After trying out a few of the Irish online shops for our equipment, I settled on Komplett about a year ago. They have good prices, a comprehensive selection and an easily navigable website. All happy out. Not quite.
A while ago, they changed their online delivery options, which I think is very confusing. I needed to purchase a SATA hard drive. Having located the item on their site, I went to purchase it.</description></item><item><title>Bess one year on</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/04/bess-one-year-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/04/bess-one-year-on/</guid><description>Bess has grown a little bit from the pup who arrived about the year ago. She is now a near fully grown German Shepard.</description></item><item><title>My 2nd Bike</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/01/new-bike-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2009/01/new-bike-2/</guid><description>I got a new bike, a Honda Hornet 250. It&amp;rsquo;s a lovely little bike, Japanese import because this model was never released outside Japan. It redlines at 16,000 RPM and can reach up to 180 Km/h. I bought it at Tallaght Superbikes and Autos. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to ride and is perfect for jinking in and out of traffic. I bought because while the cbf 250 is a great starter bike, it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it outside the city.</description></item><item><title>Bizarre line of questioning</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/06/bizarre-line-of-questioning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/06/bizarre-line-of-questioning/</guid><description>Never one to think of myself as a p.c. nazi, I have to say I was a little taken aback by a question asked of me by the FAI. I was filling out a form for my nephew so he could go to a summer soccer camp. The idea is an excellent one, and definitley helps get children out and about during the summer months. But while going through the registration process, I noticed this:</description></item><item><title>Don't mess with Bess</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/04/dont-mess-with-bess/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/04/dont-mess-with-bess/</guid><description>New pooch here as well. For some reason the bitch is called Bess. She arrived as a puppy and after a few weeks is now massive.</description></item><item><title>New bike</title><link>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/04/new-bike/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trootski.github.io/post/2008/04/new-bike/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently moved from four wheels back down to two :o
I got a Honda CBF 250. It&amp;rsquo;s going well, enjoying learning something new. And having an excuse to wear leathers is just the icing on the cake.</description></item></channel></rss>